Brainard, Charles Henry, 1817-1885. Charles Henry Brainard papers, 1795-1884 (MS Am 889.14-889.16): Guide.
Charles Henry Brainard papers,
- Brainard, Charles Henry, 1817-1885. Scrapbook, 1795-1857., 2 volumes.
  - Multiple items., Page 130
    Drew, John G. Autograph, includes address, 180 Read Street, New York.
    Sumner, Charles, 1811-1874. Autograph.
  - Publication announcement of A Large Lithographic Portrait of Dr. G. Bailey., Page 131
    Subscribers include:
    Colfax, Schuyler, 1823-1885. Autograph, includes addresss, South Bend, Indiana.
    Brigham, Jason A.? Autograph.
    Poore, Benjamin Perley, 1820-1887. Autograph, includes address, Newburyport, Massachusetts.
    Burlingame, N.? Autograph, includes address, Cambridge.
    Spinner, Francis Elias, 1802-1890. Autograph, includes address, Mohawk, New York.
    Washburn, Israel, 1813-1883. Autograph, includes address, Orono, Maine.
    Blair, J.P.? Autograph, includes address, St. Louis, Missouri.
    Decker, Charles? Autograph, includes address, Kenosha, Wisconsin.
    Seward, William Henry, 1801-1872. Autograph, includes address, Auburn.
    King, Preston, 1806-1865. Autograph, includes address, Ogdensburgh, New York.
    Hamlin, Hannibal, 1809-1891? Autograph, includes address, Hampden, Maine.
    Newspaper clipping describes D'Avignon, a prominent lithographic artist.
  - Letter recommending Charles Henry Brainard for office of Messenger of the House; Washington, 1847 December 7., Page 132
    Includes signatures of:
    King, Daniel P. (Daniel Putnam), 1801-1850.
    Hudson, Charles, 1795-1881.
    Hale, Artemas, 1783-1882.
    Roshwell, J.?
    Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848.
    Grinnell, Joseph, 1788-1885.
    George Arkman?
    Abbott, Amos, 1786-1868.
  - Multiple items., Page 133
    Chih-ta-jin, Minister of China, autograph.
    Sun-ta-jin, Minister of China, autograph.
    Autographs are in Chinese characters.
  - Multiple items., Page 134
    Fung-jee, Attaché, autograph.
    Jn. Têh, from Peking, China. Autograph.
  - Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848. Letter (facsimile) to Edmund Quincy, 1838 July 28., Page 135
  - Channing, W.H. (William Henry), 1810-1884. Letter to unidentified recipient; Boston, Massachusetts, 1849 January 8., Page 136
  - Lieber, Francis, 1800-1872. Letter to unidentified recipient; Columbia, South Carolina, 1848 January 15., Page 137
  - Multiple items., Page 139
    Snelling, William Joseph, 1804-1848. Autograph pasted onto an epigram.
    Champagny, Jean-Baptiste Nompère de, duc de Cadore, 1756-1834. Autograph note; Paris, France, 1811 January 26, in French.
    Johnson, Richard M. (Richard Mentor), 1780-1850. Autograph note. 1848 February 8.
  - Beattie, William, 1793-1875. Letter to unidentified recipient; London, England, 1833 March 27., Page 140
  - Multiple items., Page 141
    Addressed envelope with postmark to unknown recipient, 1835 June 6.
    Addressed envelope to Postmaster in Plymouth, 1835? June 29.
    Addressed envelope with postmark, 1833 to unknown recipient.
    Addressed envelope to Lt. Col Thornhill, 1827 January 30.
    All envelopes are excised and pasted on Page.
  - Multiple items., Page 142
    Palmerston, Henry John Temple, Viscount, 1784-1865. Autograph, 1829 July 29.
    Melville, correspondent. Cut envelope addressed to Robert Trotter, Esq.; London, 1838 November 15.
  - Multiple items., Page 143
    Royall, Anne Newport, 1769-1854. Autograph.
    Adams, Charles Francis, 1807-1886. Letter excerpt to unknown recipient.
    Brisbane, Albert, 1809-1890. Letter excerpt to unknown recipient.
  - Letter recommending Charles Henry Brainard for a clerkship in the New York Custom House by members of the Thirtieth Congress, 1849 February 24., Page 144
    Signatures include:
    Chapman, John G. (John Grant), 1798-1856.
    Canby, R.S.
    Crowell, John, 1801-1883.
    Slingerland, John I., 1804-1862.
    Blackmar, Esbon.
    Rockwell, Julius, 1805-1888.
    Strohm, John, 1793-1884.
    Nes, Henry, 1799-1850.
    Putnam, Harvey.
    Baker, E.D.?